Hye Won (Nicole) Hwang

Evanston, IL +1-872-888-5568 hyehwang2023@u.northwestern.edu

Self-motivated and proactive prospective data scientist with project experience in machine learning and mobile application development. **Creative and versatile** individual with excellent problem-solving skills utilizing data science. Diversified skills in **analysing and organizing data**, **adapting in fast-paced environment**, and **contributing to positive team morale**.

EXPERIENCE

HONDA R&D Remote

Data Science Consultant

Oct 2022-Current

- Developing a cost prediction model using machine learning techniques to forecast future costs and optimize budget planning.
- Liaising with 4 data science students, 2 MBA students, ZealStrat consulting, and Honda R&D to develop a machine learning model that can be implemented to make data driven decision.

PROPWAVE Seoul, South Korea

Data Science Intern

April 2022–May 2022

- Assisted in developing image-based empty parking slot detection code in Python using CV2 (OpenCV) library to identify empty parking spaces in real-time video streams from cameras installed in a parking lot.
- Implemented image preprocessing techniques (e.g. filtering, thresholding) to enhance the contrast and clarity of the input images and improve the accuracy of the detection algorithm
- Tested and evaluated the performance of the empty parking slot detection code using metrics such as accuracy, precision, and recall

YONSEI UNIVERSITY Seoul, South Korea

Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant

Sept 2019-Aug 2021

- Designed, modeled, and experimented research on bioactive peptides.
- Utilized R to preprocess, cluster and visualize genome and peptide data.
- Published research paper as first author at JAFC (IF 5.279).
- Procured research grant from Amore Pacific Co.

PROJECT

Nutri-AI Feb 2022 – Apr 2023

Flutter-based food image detection application for logging meals and recommending iHerb supplements. (www.github.com/Nutri-AI)

- participated in end-to-end development from...
 - 1. creating database schema and utilizing AWS DynamoDB/S3,
 - 2. building backend API using FastAPI,
 - 3. training image detection model with Yolov3,
 - 4. deploying model using ONNX/ ONNX runtime,
 - 5. deploying service using docker and EC2,
 - 6. developing Flutter mobile application.

Project received 1st place in the SK Planet's data science bootcamp.

EDUCATION

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

Master of Science in Analytics

Sept 2022 – Dec 2023

Evanston, IL

YONSEI UNIVERSITY

Master of Science in Bio-industrial Engineering

Lab. of Food and Biosystems Engineering

Seoul, South Korea

Sept 2019 – Aug 2021

YONSEI UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science in Biotechnology

Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2015 - Aug 2019

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Python (TensorFlow, Fast-API)
- JavaScript (Node JS, EJS)
- Dart (Flutter)
- SQL (MySQL)
- AWS (DynamoDB, S3, EC2)
- Git (GitHub)
- HTML/CSS

PUBLICATIONS

Lee, Ji-Young, Hwang H.W. et al. (2022) "A Genomics-Based Semirational Approach for Expanding the Postbiotic Potential of Collagen Peptides Using Lactobacillaceae." Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry.

Hwang, H. W., & Lee, D. W. (2019). Prebiotics: An overview of current researches and industrial applications. Food Science and Industry, 52(3), 241-260.

LANGUAGES

Korean: fluent

English: fluent, TOEFL 117/120